<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="https://docs.freebsd.org/en/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 12. Security</title><link>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/books/porters-handbook/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/books/porters-handbook/security/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="security-intro">12.1. Why Security is So Important&lt;a class="anchor" href="#security-intro">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Bugs are occasionally introduced to the software.
Arguably, the most dangerous of them are those opening security vulnerabilities.
From the technical viewpoint, such vulnerabilities are to be closed by exterminating the bugs that caused them.
However, the policies for handling mere bugs and security vulnerabilities are very different.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>A typical small bug affects only those users who have enabled some combination of options triggering the bug.
The developer will eventually release a patch followed by a new version of the software,
free of the bug, but the majority of users will not take the trouble of upgrading immediately because the bug has never vexed them.
A critical bug that may cause data loss represents a graver issue.
Nevertheless, prudent users know that a lot of possible accidents, besides software bugs, are likely to lead to data loss, and so they make backups of important data; in addition, a critical bug will be discovered really soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 16. Security</title><link>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/books/handbook/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/books/handbook/security/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="security-synopsis">16.1. Synopsis&lt;a class="anchor" href="#security-synopsis">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Hundreds of standard practices have been authored about how to secure systems and networks, and as a user of FreeBSD, understanding how to protect against attacks and intruders is a must.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In this chapter, several fundamentals and techniques will be discussed.
The FreeBSD system comes with multiple layers of security, and many more third party utilities may be added to enhance security.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This chapter covers:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Basic FreeBSD system security concepts.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The various crypt mechanisms available in FreeBSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to configure TCP Wrappers for use with &lt;a href="https://man.freebsd.org/cgi/man.cgi?query=inetd&amp;amp;sektion=8&amp;amp;format=html">inetd(8)&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up Kerberos on FreeBSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to configure and use OpenSSH on FreeBSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to use OpenSSL on FreeBSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to use file system ACLs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to use pkg to audit third party software packages installed from the Ports Collection.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to utilize FreeBSD security advisories.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What Process Accounting is and how to enable it on FreeBSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to control user resources using login classes or the resource limits database.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What is Capsicum and a basic example.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 18. Mandatory Access Control</title><link>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/books/handbook/mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/books/handbook/mac/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="mac-synopsis">18.1. Synopsis&lt;a class="anchor" href="#mac-synopsis">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>FreeBSD supports security extensions based on the POSIX®.1e draft.
These security mechanisms include file system Access Control Lists (&lt;a href="../security/#fs-acl">“Access Control Lists”&lt;/a>) and Mandatory Access Control (MAC).
MAC allows access control modules to be loaded in order to implement security policies.
Some modules provide protections for a narrow subset of the system, hardening a particular service.
Others provide comprehensive labeled security across all subjects and objects.
The mandatory part of the definition indicates that enforcement of controls is performed by administrators and the operating system.
This is in contrast to the default security mechanism of Discretionary Access Control (DAC) where enforcement is left to the discretion of users.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Appendix B. Bibliography</title><link>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/books/handbook/bibliography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.freebsd.org/en/books/handbook/bibliography/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>While manual pages provide a definitive reference for individual pieces of the FreeBSD operating system, they seldom illustrate how to put the pieces together to make the whole operating system run smoothly.
For this, there is no substitute for a good book or users&amp;#39; manual on UNIX® system administration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="bibliography-freebsd">B.1. FreeBSD Bibliography&lt;a class="anchor" href="#bibliography-freebsd">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Absolute FreeBSD: The Complete Guide To FreeBSD&lt;/strong>, Third Edition, published by &lt;a href="https://nostarch.com/absfreebsd3">No Starch Press&lt;/a>, 2018. ISBN: 978-1593278922&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FreeBSD Mastery: Storage Essentials&lt;/strong>, published by &lt;a href="https://www.tiltedwindmillpress.com/product/freebsd-mastery-storage-essentials/">Tilted Windmill Press&lt;/a>, 2014. ISBN: 978-1642350098&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FreeBSD Mastery: Specialty Filesystems&lt;/strong>, published by &lt;a href="https://www.tiltedwindmillpress.com/product/fmspf/">Tilted Windmill Press&lt;/a>, 2015. ISBN: 978-1642350111&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FreeBSD Mastery: ZFS&lt;/strong>, published by &lt;a href="https://www.tiltedwindmillpress.com/product/fmzfs/">Tilted Windmill Press&lt;/a>, 2015. ISBN: 978-1642350005&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FreeBSD Mastery: Advanced ZFS&lt;/strong>, published by &lt;a href="https://www.tiltedwindmillpress.com/product/fmaz/">Tilted Windmill Press&lt;/a>, 2016. ISBN: 978-0692688687&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FreeBSD Mastery: Jails&lt;/strong>, published by &lt;a href="https://www.tiltedwindmillpress.com/product/fmjail/">Tilted Windmill Press&lt;/a>, 2019. ISBN: 978-1642350241&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FreeBSD Device Drivers: A Guide for the Intrepid&lt;/strong>, published by &lt;a href="https://nostarch.com/bsddrivers.htm">No Starch Press&lt;/a>, 2012. ISBN: 978-1593272043&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Design And Implementation Of The Freebsd Operating System&lt;/strong>, Second Edition, published by &lt;a href="https://www.pearson.com/store/p/design-and-implementation-of-the-freebsd-operating-system-the/P200000000463/9780321968975">Pearson Education, Inc.&lt;/a>, 2014. ISBN: 978-0321968975&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>UNIX and Linux System Administration Handbook&lt;/strong>, Fifth Edition, published by &lt;a href="https://www.pearson.com/en-us/subject-catalog/p/unix-and-linux-system-administration-handbook/P200000000513/9780137460359">Pearson Education, Inc.&lt;/a>, 2017. ISBN: 978-0134277554&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Designing BSD Rootkits&lt;/strong>, published by &lt;a href="https://nostarch.com/rootkits.htm">No Starch Press&lt;/a>, 2007. ISBN: 978-1593271428&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FreeBSD Jails using VNETs&lt;/strong>, published in &lt;a href="https://rderik.gumroad.com/l/uwOLZ">gumroad&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>