<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UHCI on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/UHCI/</link><description>Recent content in UHCI on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/UHCI/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 13. USB Devices</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/arch-handbook/usb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/arch-handbook/usb/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="usb-intro">13.1. Introduction&lt;a class="anchor" href="#usb-intro">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The Universal Serial Bus (USB) is a new way of attaching devices to personal computers. The bus architecture features two-way communication and has been developed as a response to devices becoming smarter and requiring more interaction with the host. USB support is included in all current PC chipsets and is therefore available in all recently built PCs. Apple’s introduction of the USB-only iMac has been a major incentive for hardware manufacturers to produce USB versions of their devices. The future PC specifications specify that all legacy connectors on PCs should be replaced by one or more USB connectors, providing generic plug and play capabilities. Support for USB hardware was available at a very early stage in NetBSD and was developed by Lennart Augustsson for the NetBSD project. The code has been ported to FreeBSD and we are currently maintaining a shared code base. For the implementation of the USB subsystem a number of features of USB are important.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>