<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/network/</link><description>Recent content in Network on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 7. Network</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/network/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="network-synopsis">7.1. Synopsis&lt;a class="anchor" href="#network-synopsis">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This chapter delves into the topic of network configuration and performance, showcasing the robust networking capabilities of the FreeBSD operating system.
Whether working with wired or wireless networks, this chapter provides a comprehensive guide to configuring and optimizing network connectivity in FreeBSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Before diving into the details, it is beneficial for readers to have a basic understanding of networking concepts such as protocols, network interfaces, and addressing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This chapter covers:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 32. Network Servers</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/network-servers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/network-servers/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="network-servers-synopsis">32.1. Synopsis&lt;a class="anchor" href="#network-servers-synopsis">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This chapter covers some of the more frequently used network services on UNIX® systems.
This includes installing, configuring, testing, and maintaining many different types of network services.
Example configuration files are included throughout this chapter for reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>By the end of this chapter, readers will know:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to manage the inetd daemon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up the Network File System (NFS).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up the Network Information Server (NIS) for centralizing and sharing user accounts.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set FreeBSD up to act as an LDAP server or client&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up automatic network settings using DHCP.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up a Domain Name Server (DNS).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up the Apache HTTP Server.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up a File Transfer Protocol (FTP) server.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up a file and print server for Windows® clients using Samba.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to synchronize the time and date, and set up a time server using the Network Time Protocol (NTP).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to set up iSCSI.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Filtering Bridges</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/filtering-bridges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/filtering-bridges/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph abstract-title">
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Often it is useful to divide one physical network (like an Ethernet) into two separate segments without having to create subnets, and use a router to link them together.
The device that connects the two networks in this way is called a bridge.
A FreeBSD system with two network interfaces is enough to act as a bridge.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>A bridge works by scanning the addresses of MAC level (Ethernet addresses) of the devices connected to each of its network interfaces and then forwarding the traffic between the two networks only if the source and the destination are on different segments.
Under many points of view a bridge is similar to an Ethernet switch with only two ports.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>