<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UFS on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/UFS/</link><description>Recent content in UFS on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/UFS/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 21. GEOM: Modular Disk Transformation Framework</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/geom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/geom/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="geom-synopsis">21.1. Synopsis&lt;a class="anchor" href="#geom-synopsis">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In FreeBSD, the GEOM framework permits access and control to classes, such as Master Boot Records and BSD labels, through the use of providers, or the disk devices in &lt;span class="filename">/dev&lt;/span>.
By supporting various software RAID configurations, GEOM transparently provides access to the operating system and operating system utilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>This chapter covers the use of disks under the GEOM framework in FreeBSD.
This includes the major RAID control utilities which use the framework for configuration.
This chapter is not a definitive guide to RAID configurations and only GEOM-supported RAID classifications are discussed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Implementing UFS Journaling on a Desktop PC</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/gjournal-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/gjournal-desktop/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph abstract-title">
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>A journaling file system uses a log to record all transactions that take place in the file system, and preserves its integrity in the event of a system crash or power failure.
Although it is still possible to lose unsaved changes to files, journaling almost completely eliminates the possibility of file system corruption caused by an unclean shutdown.
It also shortens to a minimum the time required for after-failure file system checking.
Although the UFS file system employed by FreeBSD does not implement journaling itself, the new journal class of the GEOM framework in FreeBSD 7.&lt;em>X&lt;/em> can be used to provide file system independent journaling.
This article explains how to implement UFS journaling on a typical desktop PC scenario.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>