<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtual Machine on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/virtual-machine/</link><description>Recent content in Virtual Machine on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/virtual-machine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Design elements of the FreeBSD VM system</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/vm-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/vm-design/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph abstract-title">
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Matthew Dillon &amp;lt;&lt;a href="mailto:dillon@apollo.backplane.com">dillon@apollo.backplane.com&lt;/a>&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The title is really just a fancy way of saying that I am going to attempt to describe the whole VM enchilada, hopefully in a way that everyone can follow.
For the last year I have concentrated on a number of major kernel subsystems within FreeBSD, with the VM and Swap subsystems being the most interesting and NFS being &amp;#34;a necessary chore&amp;#34;.
I rewrote only small portions of the code. In the VM arena the only major rewrite I have done is to the swap subsystem.
Most of my work was cleanup and maintenance, with only moderate code rewriting and no major algorithmic adjustments within the VM subsystem.
The bulk of the VM subsystem’s theoretical base remains unchanged and a lot of the credit for the modernization effort in the last few years belongs to John Dyson and David Greenman.
Not being a historian like Kirk I will not attempt to tag all the various features with peoples names, since I will invariably get it wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>