<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BSD on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/BSD/</link><description>Recent content in BSD on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/BSD/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Explaining BSD</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/explaining-bsd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/explaining-bsd/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph abstract-title">
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In the open source world, the word &amp;#34;Linux&amp;#34; is almost synonymous with &amp;#34;Operating System&amp;#34;, but it is not the only open source UNIX® operating system.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>So what is the secret? Why is BSD not better known? This white paper addresses these and other questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Throughout this paper, differences between BSD and Linux will be noted &lt;em>like this&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;hr/>

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="what-is-bsd">1. What is BSD?&lt;a class="anchor" href="#what-is-bsd">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>BSD stands for &amp;#34;Berkeley Software Distribution&amp;#34;.
It is the name of distributions of source code from the University of California, Berkeley, which were originally extensions to AT&amp;amp;T’s Research UNIX® operating system.
Several open source operating system projects are based on a release of this source code known as 4.4BSD-Lite.
In addition, they comprise a number of packages from other Open Source projects, including notably the GNU project.
The overall operating system comprises:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>The Design and Implementation of the 4.4BSD Operating System</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/design-44bsd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/design-44bsd/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;hr/>

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="overview">2.1. Design Overview of 4.4BSD&lt;a class="anchor" href="#overview">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="sect2">
&lt;h3 id="overview-facilities">2.1.1. 4.4BSD Facilities and the Kernel&lt;a class="anchor" href="#overview-facilities">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The 4.4BSD kernel provides four basic facilities: processes, a filesystem, communications, and system startup.
This section outlines where each of these four basic services is described in this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="olist arabic">
&lt;ol class="arabic">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Processes constitute a thread of control in an address space. Mechanisms for creating, terminating, and otherwise controlling processes are described in Chapter 4. The system multiplexes separate virtual-address spaces for each process; this memory management is discussed in Chapter 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The user interface to the filesystem and devices is similar; common aspects are discussed in Chapter 6. The filesystem is a set of named files, organized in a tree-structured hierarchy of directories, and of operations to manipulate them, as presented in Chapter 7. Files reside on physical media such as disks. 4.4BSD supports several organizations of data on the disk, as set forth in Chapter 8. Access to files on remote machines is the subject of Chapter 9. Terminals are used to access the system; their operation is the subject of Chapter 10.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Communication mechanisms provided by traditional UNIX systems include simplex reliable byte streams between related processes (see pipes, Section 11.1), and notification of exceptional events (see signals, Section 4.7). 4.4BSD also has a general interprocess-communication facility. This facility, described in Chapter 11, uses access mechanisms distinct from those of the filesystem, but, once a connection is set up, a process can access it as though it were a pipe. There is a general networking framework, discussed in Chapter 12, that is normally used as a layer underlying the IPC facility. Chapter 13 describes a particular networking implementation in detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Any real operating system has operational issues, such as how to start it running. Startup and operational issues are described in Chapter 14.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>