<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Porting on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/zh-tw/tags/porting/</link><description>Recent content in Porting on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>zh-tw</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/zh-tw/tags/porting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 12. Security</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/zh-tw/books/porters-handbook/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/zh-tw/books/porters-handbook/security/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="security-intro">12.1. Why Security is So Important&lt;a class="anchor" href="#security-intro">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Bugs are occasionally introduced to the software.
Arguably, the most dangerous of them are those opening security vulnerabilities.
From the technical viewpoint, such vulnerabilities are to be closed by exterminating the bugs that caused them.
However, the policies for handling mere bugs and security vulnerabilities are very different.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>A typical small bug affects only those users who have enabled some combination of options triggering the bug.
The developer will eventually release a patch followed by a new version of the software,
free of the bug, but the majority of users will not take the trouble of upgrading immediately because the bug has never vexed them.
A critical bug that may cause data loss represents a graver issue.
Nevertheless, prudent users know that a lot of possible accidents, besides software bugs, are likely to lead to data loss, and so they make backups of important data; in addition, a critical bug will be discovered really soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 13. Dos and Don'ts</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/zh-tw/books/porters-handbook/porting-dads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/zh-tw/books/porters-handbook/porting-dads/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="dads-intro">13.1. Introduction&lt;a class="anchor" href="#dads-intro">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Here is a list of common dos and don’ts that are encountered during the porting process.
Check the port against this list, but also check ports in the &lt;a href="https://bugs.FreeBSD.org/search/">PR database&lt;/a> that others have submitted.
Submit any comments on ports as described in &lt;a href="https://docs.freebsd.org/zh-tw/articles/contributing/#CONTRIB-GENERAL">Bug Reports and General Commentary&lt;/a>.
Checking ports in the PR database will both make it faster for us to commit them, and prove that you know what you are doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>