<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ports on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/ports/</link><description>Recent content in Ports on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/ports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 1. Introduction</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/porting-why/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/porting-why/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;!-- toc disabled -->
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The FreeBSD Ports Collection is the way almost everyone installs applications (&amp;#34;ports&amp;#34;) on FreeBSD.
Like everything else about FreeBSD, it is primarily a volunteer effort.
It is important to keep this in mind when reading this document.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In FreeBSD, anyone may submit a new port, or volunteer to maintain an existing unmaintained port.
No special commit privilege is needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 2. Making a New Port</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/new-port/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/new-port/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;!-- toc disabled -->
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Interested in making a new port, or upgrading existing ports? Great!&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>What follows are some guidelines for creating a new port for FreeBSD.
To upgrade an existing port, read this, then read &lt;a href="../upgrading/#port-upgrading">Upgrading a Port&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>When this document is not sufficiently detailed, refer to &lt;span class="filename">/usr/ports/Mk/bsd.port.mk&lt;/span>, which is included by all port &lt;span class="filename">Makefiles&lt;/span>.
Even those not hacking &lt;span class="filename">Makefile&lt;/span>s daily can gain much knowledge from it.
Additionally, specific questions can be sent to the &lt;a href="https://lists.FreeBSD.org/subscription/freebsd-ports">FreeBSD ports mailing list&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 4. Slow Porting</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/slow-porting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/slow-porting/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Okay, so it was not that simple, and the port required some modifications to get it to work.
In this section, we will explain, step by step, how to modify it to get it to work with the ports paradigm.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="slow-work">4.1. How Things Work&lt;a class="anchor" href="#slow-work">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>First, this is the sequence of events which occurs when the user first types &lt;code>make&lt;/code> in the port’s directory.
Having &lt;span class="filename">bsd.port.mk&lt;/span> in another window while reading this really helps to understand it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 4. Installing Applications: Packages and Ports</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/ports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/ports/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="ports-synopsis">4.1. Synopsis&lt;a class="anchor" href="#ports-synopsis">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>FreeBSD is bundled with a rich collection of system tools as part of the base system.
In addition, FreeBSD provides two complementary technologies for installing third-party software: the FreeBSD Ports Collection,
for installing from source, and packages, for installing from pre-built binaries.
Either method may be used to install software from local media or from the network.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>After reading this chapter, you will know:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="ulist">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The difference between binary packages and ports.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to find third-party software that has been ported to FreeBSD.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to manage binary packages using pkg.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to build third-party software from source using the Ports Collection.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to find the files installed with the application for post-installation configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What to do if a software installation fails.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 7. Flavors</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/flavors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/flavors/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="flavors-intro">7.1. An Introduction to Flavors&lt;a class="anchor" href="#flavors-intro">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Flavors are a way to have multiple variations of a port.
The port is built multiple times, with variations.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>For example, a port can have a normal version with many features and quite a few dependencies, and a light &amp;#34;lite&amp;#34; version with only basic features and minimal dependencies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Another example could be, a port can have a GTK flavor and a QT flavor, depending on which toolkit it uses.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 12. Security</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/security/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="security-intro">12.1. Why Security is So Important&lt;a class="anchor" href="#security-intro">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Bugs are occasionally introduced to the software.
Arguably, the most dangerous of them are those opening security vulnerabilities.
From the technical viewpoint, such vulnerabilities are to be closed by exterminating the bugs that caused them.
However, the policies for handling mere bugs and security vulnerabilities are very different.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>A typical small bug affects only those users who have enabled some combination of options triggering the bug.
The developer will eventually release a patch followed by a new version of the software,
free of the bug, but the majority of users will not take the trouble of upgrading immediately because the bug has never vexed them.
A critical bug that may cause data loss represents a graver issue.
Nevertheless, prudent users know that a lot of possible accidents, besides software bugs, are likely to lead to data loss, and so they make backups of important data; in addition, a critical bug will be discovered really soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 13. Dos and Don'ts</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/porting-dads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/porting-dads/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="dads-intro">13.1. Introduction&lt;a class="anchor" href="#dads-intro">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Here is a list of common dos and don’ts that are encountered during the porting process.
Check the port against this list, but also check ports in the &lt;a href="https://bugs.FreeBSD.org/search/">PR database&lt;/a> that others have submitted.
Submit any comments on ports as described in &lt;a href="https://docs.freebsd.org/en/articles/contributing/#CONTRIB-GENERAL">Bug Reports and General Commentary&lt;/a>.
Checking ports in the PR database will both make it faster for us to commit them, and prove that you know what you are doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 16. Keeping Up</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/keeping-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/porters-handbook/keeping-up/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The FreeBSD Ports Collection is constantly changing.
Here is some information on how to keep up.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="freshports">16.1. FreshPorts&lt;a class="anchor" href="#freshports">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>One of the easiest ways to learn about updates that have already been committed is by subscribing to &lt;a href="https://www.FreshPorts.org/">FreshPorts&lt;/a>.
Multiple ports can be monitored.
Maintainers are strongly encouraged to subscribe, because they will receive notification of not only their own changes, but also any changes that any other FreeBSD committer has made.
(These are often necessary to keep up with changes in the underlying ports framework-although it would be most polite to receive an advance heads-up from those committing such changes, sometimes this is overlooked or impractical.
Also, in some cases, the changes are very minor in nature.
We expect everyone to use their best judgement in these cases.)&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>