<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Filtering on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/filtering/</link><description>Recent content in Filtering on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/filtering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 33. Firewalls</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/firewalls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/firewalls/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="firewalls-intro">33.1. Synopsis&lt;a class="anchor" href="#firewalls-intro">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Firewalls make it possible to filter the incoming and outgoing traffic that flows through a system.
A firewall can use one or more sets of &amp;#34;rules&amp;#34; to inspect network packets as they come in or go out of network connections and either allows the traffic through or blocks it.
The rules of a firewall can inspect one or more characteristics of the packets such as the protocol type, source or destination host address, and source or destination port.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Filtering Bridges</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/filtering-bridges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/articles/filtering-bridges/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph abstract-title">
&lt;p>Abstract&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Often it is useful to divide one physical network (like an Ethernet) into two separate segments without having to create subnets, and use a router to link them together.
The device that connects the two networks in this way is called a bridge.
A FreeBSD system with two network interfaces is enough to act as a bridge.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>A bridge works by scanning the addresses of MAC level (Ethernet addresses) of the devices connected to each of its network interfaces and then forwarding the traffic between the two networks only if the source and the destination are on different segments.
Under many points of view a bridge is similar to an Ethernet switch with only two ports.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>