<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Organization on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/organization/</link><description>Recent content in Organization on FreeBSD Documentation Portal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>BSD 2-clause 'Simplified' License</copyright><atom:link href="http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/tags/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Preface</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/preface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/handbook/preface/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="sect1">
&lt;h2 id="preface-audience">Intended Audience&lt;a class="anchor" href="#preface-audience">&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="sectionbody">
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>The FreeBSD newcomer will find that the first section of this book guides the user through the FreeBSD installation process and gently introduces the concepts and conventions that underpin UNIX®.
Working through this section requires little more than the desire to explore, and the ability to take on board new concepts as they are introduced.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Once you have traveled this far, the second, far larger, section of the Handbook is a comprehensive reference to all manner of topics of interest to FreeBSD system administrators.
Some of these chapters may recommend that you do some prior reading, and this is noted in the synopsis at the beginning of each chapter.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Chapter 4. Documentation Directory Structure</title><link>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/fdp-primer/structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://172.16.201.134:1313/en/books/fdp-primer/structure/</guid><description>&lt;div id="preamble">
&lt;div class="sectionbody">

&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>Files and directories in the &lt;strong>doc/&lt;/strong> tree follow a structure meant to:&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="olist arabic">
&lt;ol class="arabic">
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make it easy to automate converting the document to other formats.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Promote consistency between the different documentation organizations, to make it easier to switch between working on different documents.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make it easy to decide where in the tree new documentation should be placed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="paragraph">
&lt;p>In addition, the documentation tree must accommodate documents in many different languages.
It is important that the documentation tree structure does not enforce any particular defaults or cultural preferences.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>